Dru Lang

422 E 75th Apt 1RW New York, NY 10021

(336) 575-3816 drulang@gmail.com http://drulang.com

Experienced software engineer offering a strong skill set in iOS and backend development with an interest in startups, mobile, marketing, and design.

# <u>TripAdvisor</u>, New York, NY — Software Engineer II

March 2017 - Present

TripAdvisor is a travel review company that serves over 280 million unique visitors per month.

- Implement features for both iOS and Android that over 1 million people use daily
- Successfully launched an initiative to bring mobile ads to the map interface which brings in an additional 3 million dollars per year of additional revenue
- Implement features and bug fixes with a primary focus on the map interface
- Work closely with the designer to strike a balance between aesthetic and practical
- Continually write UI Snapshot tests and unit tests

### PERSONAL PROJECTS

For a complete listing visit http://drulang.com

## Ikeono, New York, NY

The check engine light for your bike. Ikeono monitors your bike's distance and alerts you when it needs service.

- Created iOS UI/UX in Sketch
- Implemented the iOS app in Swift 4
- Created landing page and social media accounts to gauge interest
- Implemented REST API with Django REST Framework
- Setup backend and dev servers running CentOS 7, PostgreSQL 10, Django 2.0

#### **Dental WebSense**, New York, NY

Dental WebSense provides web and mobile solutions for dentists.

- Created iOS UI/UX and marketing materials in Sketch
- Implemented white-label iOS app that uses multiple targets to provide a customized solution
- Created website utilizing Django and Bootstrap

## PAST POSITIONS

## <u>Switch App</u>, New York, NY — Lead iOS Engineer

January 2015 - March 2017

Switch is a job matchmaking app that pairs job candidates with employers.

- Work closely with the product manager and designer to plan sprints
- Manage remote iOS engineer
- Gather product specs and translate to engineering specs
- Responsible for the app release process for beta, release candidates, and production

- Maintain provisioning profiles, schemes, targets, and certificates
- Implemented client and server side caching
- Used Realm mobile database to store user's activity
- Wrote activity feed feature which utilized caching and local storage to handle offline
- Implemented Facebook user signup and login flow
- Worked on backend, creating various endpoints needed by the mobile clients

#### **Orcatec, Remote** — *Software Engineer*

October 2013 - January 2015

Orcatec is a document ingestion engine designed to help lawyers organize and search documents during the discovery phase of a case.

- Maintain the web document viewing feature
- Added support for handling different file types (i.e. eml and msg file types)
- · Added various features such as zooming, rotation, and automatic user preference saving
- Fix and maintain the bulk document PDF rendering feature
- Refactored large portions of the codebase to be more reliable and fixed numerous bugs
- Implemented various dashboards to report system status
- Wrote extensive test coverage using Selenium test framework

# <u>Truliant Federal Credit Union</u>, Winston-Salem, NC — Application Developer

February 2012 - October 2013

- Wrote business-loan payment processor to post scheduled multi-thousand dollar payments
  - Written in Python 2.7 with OOP principles
  - Used 3rd party SOAP Web Services, Core API and raw sockets to handle data
  - Multithreaded application to significantly reduce processing time
  - High profile project that was delivered on time and a huge success
- Python programs to solve automation and business needs
  - o 20 jobs; functionality including file handling, SSH, SFTP, and HTTP scripting
  - o Brought significant automation improvements to System Operations team
  - Write ad-hoc Python programs to solve immediate business needs
  - Wrote Python web application to allow a non-technical department control a mission critical batch schedule

# <u>Truliant Federal Credit Union</u>, Winston-Salem, NC — System Operations Specialist

June 2010 - February 2012

- Maintained and monitored production batch schedule
- Wrote Python and Perl programs to automate and solve business problems
- Received "Rookie Award"
- Key leader during core conversion
- Worked heavily in creating financial job scheduling
- Led install, documentation, and training of UC4's Application Manager

# **EDUCATION**

## **Appalachian State University** — B.S. Computer Science

2005 - 2010 Boone, North Carolina

## SKILLS

Languages

iOS Frameworks Auto Layout, Core Data, Realm, Core Location, HLS, Core

Animation, Store Kit, Crashalytics, Alamofire, AVFoundation, APNS

**Other Frameworks** Django, Bootstrap, Flask, Celery, Django REST Framework

Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server, SQLite, Redis

Systems CentOS 7, iOS, tvOS, OS X

**Software** Xcode 9, Vim, Git, Mercurial, VirtualBox, Charles Proxy, Sketch, Fabric,

Mixpanel